Alexander Burr

Email alex@alexburr.com
Web www.alexburr.com

LinkedIn alexanderburr
GitHub alexburr

Dribbble pokealex **JSFiddle** alexburr

"Alex's technical knowledge of the web is outstanding. He is an expert on web standards, web content management, user interface design and development, social media, business process improvement, browser compatibility, and many other areas. He is equally adept working in both open-source and enterprise technologies and programming languages.

"Alex creates exceptional user experiences, helping stakeholders focus on goals and objectives before designing a web site which will meet user needs. He has a keen understanding of how to structure roles on a web project in order to achieve long-term success within the company, and is able to create models and visualizations supporting these perspectives."

—Zach Roth, Project Director, URMC

Competencies & Skills

Project management concepts including life cycle methodology, needs assessment and usability, information architecture, content strategy, SEO and conversion, and analytics

18 years experience in web development and user interface design

Server-side programming: ASP.Net with C#, PHP, ColdFusion

Client-side templating: Razor, Smarty, Nancy

Web frameworks: ASP.Net MVC, Web API, Codelgniter, ColdFusion on

Wheels

 ${\bf Content\ management:\ WordPress,\ Umbraco,\ Textpattern,\ and\ Cascade}$

Serve

Wireframing and design: Visio, Adobe Photoshop, Balsamiq, Axure RP

Client-side frameworks: AngularJS, React
Database experience: SQL Server, MySQL
Version control: Git, Mercurial, Subversion, TFS

Environments: Windows/IIS and Linux/Apache

Experience

Software Engineer, Pharos Systems International

June 2012-present

Designed and developed web applications for the managed print space.

Lead Web Developer, University of Rochester Medical Center July 2010–June 2012

Designed and developed web applications for use in various institutional business processes and workflows.

Senior Web Developer, University of Rochester Medical Center September 2007—June 2010

Designed and developed enterprise-level and multiple department-level websites

Production Manager, Cazbah

September 2004–September 2007

Managed a production team of two specialists, and designed/developed of multiple client e-commerce websites.

Web Developer, Element K

October 2003–December 2003

Developed of co-brands for Element K's Learning Management Systems. Reshaped client-supplied content for use in the LMS.

Software Engineer, AHT

June 2000–July 2002

Developed web applications for print server management software and product licensing servers.

Additional Projects

Groove Juice Swing

Ongoing

Content strategist, designer/developer for this website for a dance instruction group. Also designer/developer for various event websites, including https://www.groovejuiceswing.com and https://www.stompology.com

Yehoodi

2009-2017

Designer/developer for this social website for a nationwide swing dance community. https://www.yehoodi.com

Education

Rochester Institute of Technology BS in Information Technology (May 2000)